Mss.Rec.184 Mss.Rec.184
American Philosophical Society
- Audio recordings
  - Kayman, 1967-06-13; 15-06; 1.0 .mp3; 00:07:27; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; Miller, Sam
    Cocopa transcription and English translation found in the James M. Crawford papers (MS Coll. 66). Published version in James M. Crawford's "Cocopa Texts" (University of California Press, 1983). This program is a copy made to sound tape reel by the collector of APSdigrec_2989. See Related Recording.
  - Špac kwamay, 1967; 15-07; 1.0 .mp3; 00:44:49; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; Miller, Sam
    "Špac kwamay" is a personage in the narrated story. Cocopa transcription and English translation found in the James M. Crawford papers (MS Coll. 66). Published version in James M. Crawford's "Cocopa Texts" (University of California Press, 1983). This program is a copy made to sound tape reel by the collector of APSdigrec_2990. See Related Recording.
  - Cocopa song, 1963-03-06; 15-08; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:05; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; Thomas, Josephine
  - Cocopa coyote story, 1963-03-06; 15-09; 1.0 .mp3; 00:05:04; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; Thomas, Josephine; Thomas, Mary
    Cocopa transcription and English translation found in the James M. Crawford papers (MS Coll. 66). Published version in James M. Crawford's "Cocopa Texts" (University of California Press, 1983). This program is a copy made to sound tape reel by the collector of APSdigrec_2957. See Related Recording.
  - Cocopa conversation and song, 1963-03-06; 15-10; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:49; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; Thomas, Josephine; Thomas, Mary
    Cocopa conversation, followed by a song. This program is a copy made to sound tape reel by the collector of APSdigrec_2958. See Related Recording.
  - Cocopa words and conversation, 1963-03-06; 15-11; 1.0 .mp3; 00:04:38; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; Thomas, Josephine; Thomas, Mary
    This program is an excerpted copy made to sound tape reel by the collector of APSdigrec_2959. See Related Recording.
  - Josephine Thomas sings at Estrella Park (6 songs), 1963; 15-12; 1.0 .mp3; 00:09:22; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; Thomas, Josephine
    This program is a copy made to sound tape reel by the collector of APSdigrec_2963. See Related Recording.
  - Song: 4 parts (about a little bird), 1963-06-28; 15-13; 1.0 .mp3; 00:10:15; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; Huck, Charlie
  - Diegueño text (message to the Cocopas), 1963; 16-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:28; Couro, Ted; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-
    This program is a copy made to sound tape reel by the collector of APSdigrec_2966. See Related Recording.
  - Conversation and Cocopa coyote story, 1963; 16-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:06:03; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; Thomas, Mary
    Cocopa transcription and English translation found in the James M. Crawford papers (MS Coll. 66). Published version in James M. Crawford's "Cocopa Texts" (University of California Press, 1983). This program is a copy made to sound tape reel by the collector of APSdigrec_2967. See Related Recording.
  - Cocopa text, monologue, 1963; 16-03; 1.0 .mp3; 00:04:39; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; Thomas, Mary
    Cocopa transcription and English translation found in the James M. Crawford papers (MS Coll. 66). Published version in James M. Crawford's "Cocopa Texts" (University of California Press, 1983). This program is a copy made to sound tape reel by the collector of APSdigrec_2968. See Related Recording.
  - Cocopa text (a message to Mary), 1963-05; 16-04; 1.0 .mp3; 00:04:17; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; Hayes, Lillian
    Cocopa transcription and English translation found in the James M. Crawford papers (MS Coll. 66). Published version in James M. Crawford's "Cocopa Texts" (University of California Press, 1983). This program is a copy made to sound tape reel by the collector of APSdigrec_2969. See Related Recording.
  - Cocopa text (a message to Mary), 1963-05; 16-05; 1.0 .mp3; 00:00:48; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; Hayes, Victor
    Cocopa transcription and English translation found in the James M. Crawford papers (MS Coll. 66). Published version in James M. Crawford's "Cocopa Texts" (University of California Press, 1983). This program is a copy made to sound tape reel by the collector of APSdigrec_2970. See Related Recording.
  - Yavapai text (a message to the Cocopa) and song, 1963-05-22; 16-06; 1.0 .mp3; 00:05:31; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; Gazzam, Warren
    Copy made on sound tape reel by collector of recording APSdigrec_2971. See Related Recording.
  - Creator story, 1963-06-28; 16-07; 1.0 .mp3; 00:16:31; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; Huck, Charlie
    Cocopa transcription and English translation found in the James M. Crawford papers (MS Coll. 66). Published version in James M. Crawford's "Cocopa Texts" (University of California Press, 1983). This program is a copy made to sound tape reel by the collector of APSdigrec_2976. See Related Recording.
  - Cocopa songs, 1963; 16-08; 1.0 .mp3; 00:04:29; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; Huck, Charlie
  - A Visit to My Daughter and Grandchildren, 1965; 16-09; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:19; Cocopa, Mary; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-
    Cocopa transcription and English translation found in the James M. Crawford papers (MS Coll. 66). Published version in James M. Crawford's "Cocopa Texts" (University of California Press, 1983). This program is a copy made to sound tape reel by the collector of APSdigrec_2979. See Related Recording.
  - Thoughts on the Last Day of Work with a Linguist, 1965; 16-10; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:44; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; Miller, Hope
    Cocopa transcription and English translation found in the James M. Crawford papers (MS Coll. 66). Published version in James M. Crawford's "Cocopa Texts" (University of California Press, 1983). This program is a copy made to sound tape reel by the collector of APSdigrec_2980. See Related Recording.
  - When I Was Little, 1965; 16-11; 1.0 .mp3; 00:03:31; Cocopa, Mary; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-
    Cocopa transcription and English translation found in the James M. Crawford papers (MS Coll. 66). Published version in James M. Crawford's "Cocopa Texts" (University of California Press, 1983). This program is a copy made to sound tape reel by the collector of APSdigrec_2981. See Related Recording.
  - Coyote-fox-lion story, 1963; 16-12; 1.0 .mp3; 00:28:21; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; Huck, Charlie
    Cocopa transcription and English translation found in the James M. Crawford papers (MS Coll. 66). Published version in James M. Crawford's "Cocopa Texts" (University of California Press, 1983). This program is a copy made to sound tape reel by the collector of APSdigrec_2983. See Related Recording.
  - Coyote-blackbird-yapír story, 1963; 16-13; 1.0 .mp3; 00:10:37; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; Huck, Charlie
    Cocopa transcription and English translation found in the James M. Crawford papers (MS Coll. 66). Published version in James M. Crawford's "Cocopa Texts" (University of California Press, 1983). This program is a copy made to sound tape reel by the collector of APSdigrec_2984. See Related Recording.
  - Twins story (how to have babies), 1963; 16-14; 1.0 .mp3; 00:03:57; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; Huck, Charlie
    Cocopa transcription and English translation found in the James M. Crawford papers (MS Coll. 66). Published version in James M. Crawford's "Cocopa Texts" (University of California Press, 1983). This program is a copy made to sound tape reel by the collector of APSdigrec_2985. See Related Recording.
  - Cocopa text ("sermon"), 1967-08-12; 16-15; 1.0 .mp3; 00:24:32; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; Miller, Sam
    Cocopa transcription and English translation found in the James M. Crawford papers (MS Coll. 66). Published version in James M. Crawford's "Cocopa Texts" (University of California Press, 1983). This program is a copy made to sound tape reel by the collector of APSdigrec_2991. See Related Recording.
  - Cocopa text ("mu u'kaa"), 1967-08-12; 16-16; 1.0 .mp3; 00:40:55; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; Miller, Sam
    Cocopa transcription and English translation found in the James M. Crawford papers (MS Coll. 66). Published version in James M. Crawford's "Cocopa Texts" (University of California Press, 1983). This program is a copy made to sound tape reel by the collector of APSdigrec_2992. See Related Recording.
  - Adventures of José, the Spanish Shepherd [1 of 3], 1963-06-28; 17-01; 1.0 .mp3; 01:01:58; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; Huck, Charlie
    Cocopa transcription and English translation found in the James M. Crawford papers (MS Coll. 66). Published version in James M. Crawford's "Cocopa Texts" (University of California Press, 1983). This program is a copy made to sound tape reel by the collector of same recording on APSdigrec_2986 and APSdigrec_2987. See Related Recording.
  - Adventures of José, the Spanish Shepherd [2 of 3], 1963-06-28; 17-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:32:46; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; Huck, Charlie
  - Adventures of José, the Spanish Shepherd [3 of 3], 1963-06-28; 17-03; 1.0 .mp3; 00:15:20; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; Huck, Charlie
  - Mohave bird song, 18-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:04:08; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; Thomas, Frank
    Birds--Songs and music; Mohave Indians--Music
  - Mohave bird song, 18-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:04:42; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; Thomas, Frank
  - Mohave song, 18-03; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:16; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; Thomas, Frank
    Mohave Indians--Music
  - Mohave song ("We lost the road"), 18-04; 1.0 .mp3; 00:05:04; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; Thomas, Frank
  - Mohave song ("They were there, but they're still lost"), 18-05; 1.0 .mp3; 00:05:36; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; Thomas, Frank
  - Mohave song ("The road bends the other way"), 18-06; 1.0 .mp3; 00:05:37; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; Thomas, Frank
  - Mohave song, 18-07; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:45; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; Thomas, Frank
  - Mohave song, 18-08; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:51; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; Thomas, Frank
  - Mohave song, 18-09; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:34; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; Thomas, Frank
  - Mohave song, 18-10; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:10; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; Thomas, Frank
  - Mohave song, 18-11; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:03; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; Thomas, Frank
  - Mohave song, 18-12; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:10; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; Thomas, Frank
  - Mohave song, 18-13; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:14; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; Thomas, Frank
  - Mohave song, 18-14; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:23; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; Thomas, Frank
  - Conversation about Mohave songs, 18-15; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:16; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; Thomas, Frank
  - Mobilian trade language, 1970; 19-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:50:52; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; Langley, Arzelie; Langley, Rosaline
    Discussion and inquiry into the Mobilian trade language with Arzelie Langley, who is interpreted into English by her granddaughter. Primarily in Choctaw and Koasati, with some Mobilian words and phrases.
    Elton (La.); Mobilian trade language
  - Miscellanous material, 20-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:48:26; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-
    Unidentified contents include a conversation with passages of poetry read from Allen Ginsberg's "Howl" and Shakespeare's "Romeo & Juliet"; a monologue, possibly a lecture; readings from a Russian text; a telephone conversation; the playing of a recorder; and a second conversation with a passage of fiction read out loud.
    Poetry--Recitation; Recorder (Musical instrument); Russian language
  - Navajo words and conversation, 20-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:33:04; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-
    Navajo elicitation and conversation on Navajo Indians with an unidentified consultant. Ends with brief narration in Navajo.
    Indians of North America--Arizona; Navajo Indians; Navajo Indians--Kinship; Navajo language
  - Russian text, 20-03; 1.0 .mp3; 00:19:18; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-
    A reading of an unidentified Russian text.
    Russian language--Texts
  - Unidentified English conversation, 20-04; 1.0 .mp3; 00:10:13; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-
    Conversation
  - Shoshoni medial consonants, 21-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:13:53; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; Garcia, Florence; Miller, Wick R.
    Location of recording not identified. Possibly Utah. Recorded circa 1960s. Recorded by Wick Miller.
    Shoshoni language
  - Tolowa word and phrase list, 1956-08-03; 22-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:04:55; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; Hoijer, Harry, 1904-1976; Lopez, Sam, Mrs.
    Crescent City (Calif.); Tolowa language
  - Tolowa song, 1956-08-03; 22-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:45; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; Hoijer, Harry, 1904-1976; Lopez, Sam
    Crescent City (Calif.); Tolowa Indians--Music
  - Tolowa song, 1956-08-03; 22-03; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:10; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; Lopez, Sam
  - Tolowa song, 1956-08-03; 22-04; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:04; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; Lopez, Sam
  - Tolowa song, 1956-08-03; 22-05; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:09; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; Lopez, Sam
  - Guitar and banjo music, 22-06; 1.0 .mp3; 00:06:42; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-
    Banjo--Performance; Guitar--Performance
  - Yavapai text (a message to the Cocopa) and song, 1963-05-22; 23-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:05:41; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; Gazzam, Warren
    Copy made on audiocassette by collector of recording APSdigrec_2971. See Related Recording.
    This file is a compressed, digitized version of the original. The APS Library maintains the original format (Audiocassette) as well as an uncompressed digitized version of this recording.
  - Yavapai words, 1963; 23-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:08:54; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; Gazzam, Warren
    Copy made on audiocassette by collector of recording APSdigrec_2972. See Related Recording.
  - Yuchi conversation, 1970-06; 24-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:10:55; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; George, Mrs.; Wildcat, Nancy
    Sapulpa (Okla.); Yuchi Indians--Social life and customs; Yuchi language
  - Yuchi conversation, 1970-06; 24-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:20:43; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; George, Mrs.; Wildcat, Nancy
  - Yuchi conversation and word list, 1970-06; 24-03; 1.0 .mp3; 00:19:47; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; George, Mrs.; Wildcat, Nancy
    Includes checking of animal-related terms derived from a word list collected by Frank Speck.
  - Yuchi conversation, 1970-06; 24-04; 1.0 .mp3; 00:11:37; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; George, Mrs.; Wildcat, Nancy
  - Yuchi conversation, 1970-06; 24-05; 1.0 .mp3; 00:20:59; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; George, Mrs.; Wildcat, Nancy
  - Yuchi conversation and word list, 1970-06; 24-06; 1.0 .mp3; 00:27:39; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; George, Mrs.; Wildcat, Nancy
  - Libby talking, 1970; 24-07; 1.0 .mp3; 00:10:32; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-
    Infants--Language
  - Yuchi conversation, 1970-06; 25-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:16:54; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; George, Mrs.; Wildcat, Nancy
  - Yuchi word list, 1970-06; 25-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:10:36; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; George, Mrs.; Wildcat, Nancy
    Primarily consists of a discussion of Yuchi terms for neighboring tribes in Oklahoma and elsewhere, as well as those tribes' terms for the Yuchi.
    Indians of North America--Oklahoma; Sapulpa (Okla.); Yuchi language
  - Yuchi word sets, 1970-06; 25-03; 1.0 .mp3; 00:10:17; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; Wildcat, Nancy
    Sapulpa (Okla.); Yuchi language; Yuchi language--Grammar
  - Yuchi word sets, 1970-06; 25-04; 1.0 .mp3; 00:10:42; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; Wildcat, Nancy
    Sapulpa (Okla.); Yuchi language
  - Yuchi word lists, 1970-06; 25-05; 1.0 .mp3; 00:15:12; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; Wildcat, Nancy
  - Yuchi conversation, 1970-08-01; 26-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:11:15; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; Frank, Seymour; Wildcat, Nancy
  - Yuchi conversation, 1970-08-01; 26-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:17:10; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; Frank, Seymour; Wildcat, Nancy
  - Yuchi conversation, 1970-08-01; 26-03; 1.0 .mp3; 00:19:13; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; Frank, Seymour; Wildcat, Nancy
  - Yuchi conversation, 1970-08-01; 26-04; 1.0 .mp3; 00:15:30; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; Frank, Seymour; Wildcat, Nancy
  - Yuchi conversation, 1970-08-03; 26-05; 1.0 .mp3; 00:17:37; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; Frank, Neddie; Frank, Seymour
  - Yuchi conversation, 1970-08-03; 26-06; 1.0 .mp3; 00:19:09; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; Frank, Neddie; Frank, Seymour
  - Yuchi conversation, 1970-08-03; 26-07; 1.0 .mp3; 00:09:13; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; Frank, Neddie; Frank, Seymour
  - Comments & Reminiscences about Trail of Tears, etc., 1970-08; 27-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:17:13; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; Frank, Neddie; Frank, Seymour
    Sapulpa (Okla.); Trail of Tears, 1838-1839; Yuchi Indians--History; Yuchi language
  - Yuchi bands in Oklahoma, 1970-08; 27-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:09:38; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; Frank, Neddie; Frank, Seymour
    Indians of North America--Oklahoma; Sapulpa (Okla.); Yuchi Indians
  - Yuchi Employment in Sapulpa Area, Now and in Early Days, 1970-08; 27-03; 1.0 .mp3; 00:13:55; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; Frank, Neddie; Frank, Seymour
    Sapulpa (Okla.); Yuchi Indians--Economic conditions
  - Yuchi word list, 1970-08; 27-04; 1.0 .mp3; 00:07:07; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; Wildcat, Nancy
  - Yuchi monologue, 1970-08; 27-05; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:27; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; Wildcat, Nancy
  - Baby talk, 1970; 27-06; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:31; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-
  - Koasati and Choctaw numbers, 1970-08-24; 27-07; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:43; Celestine, Phoebie; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; Thomas, Esther
    Alabama and Coushatta Indian Reservation (Tex.); Choctaw language--Number; Koasati language--Number
  - Yama, Koasati, and Choctaw word and phrase list, 1970-08-24; 27-08; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:50; Celestine, Phoebie; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; Thomas, Esther
    Alabama and Coushatta Indian Reservation (Tex.); Choctaw language; Koasati language; Mobilian trade language
  - Koasati and Choctaw word list, 1970-08-24; 27-09; 1.0 .mp3; 00:04:49; Celestine, Phoebie; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; Thomas, Esther
    Alabama and Coushatta Indian Reservation (Tex.); Choctaw language; Koasati language
  - Koasati conversation and Choctaw song, 1970-08-24; 27-10; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:44; Abbey, Aron; Celestine, Phoebie; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; Thomas, Esther
    Alabama and Coushatta Indian Reservation (Tex.); Choctaw Indians--Music; Koasati language
  - Mobilian words and phrases, 1970-08-27; 27-11; 1.0 .mp3; 01:30:40; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; Lavan, Leonard
  - Alabama words and phrases, 1970-08-24; 27-12; 1.0 .mp3; 00:05:54; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; Poncho, Maggie
    Alabama and Coushatta Indian Reservation (Tex.); Alabama language
  - Yuchi conversation, 1970-08; 28-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:43:31; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; Frank, Neddie; Frank, Seymour
    "About square ground, red root, shake root, etc."
    Bloodroot; Sapulpa (Okla.); Yuchi Indians--Medicine; Yuchi Indians--Social life and customs; Yuchi language
  - Dry weather, 1970-08; 28-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:35; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; Frank, Neddie; Frank, Seymour
    Sapulpa (Okla.); Weather; Yuchi language
  - Earthquakes & Other Reminiscences, 1970-08; 28-03; 1.0 .mp3; 00:03:37; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; Frank, Neddie; Frank, Seymour
    Earthquakes; Sapulpa (Okla.); Yuchi Indians; Yuchi language
  - More Reminiscences, 1970-08; 28-04; 1.0 .mp3; 00:13:30; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; Frank, Neddie; Frank, Seymour
    Sapulpa (Okla.); Yuchi Indians; Yuchi language
  - Reminiscences of School Days at the Mission, 1970-08; 28-05; 1.0 .mp3; 00:21:19; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; Frank, Neddie; Frank, Seymour
    Sapulpa (Okla.); Yuchi Indians--Educiation; Yuchi language
  - Yuchi conversation, 1971-08-09; 29-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:18:46; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; George, Mrs.; Wildcat, Nancy
  - Mrs. Wildcat talks about her religious work, with children, etc., 1971-08-11; 29-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:14:22; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; George, Mrs.; Wildcat, Nancy
    Church charities; Sapulpa (Okla.); Yuchi Indians--Religion; Yuchi language
  - Gardening, trip to Georgia, etc., 1971-08-11; 29-03; 1.0 .mp3; 00:15:45; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; George, Mrs.; Wildcat, Nancy
    Gardening; Georgia--Description and travel; Sapulpa (Okla.); Yuchi Indians; Yuchi language
  - Talk about Yuchis in general, 1971-08-11; 29-04; 1.0 .mp3; 00:17:39; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; George, Mrs.; Wildcat, Nancy
  - Yuchi single consonants, 1971-08-19; 29-05; 1.0 .mp3; 00:05:40; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; Wildcat, Nancy
    Sapulpa (Okla.); Yuchi language--Phonology
  - Yuchi consonant clusters, 1971-08-19; 29-06; 1.0 .mp3; 00:03:51; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; Wildcat, Nancy
    Sapulpa (Okla.); Yuchi language; Yuchi language--Phonology
  - Yuchi minimal pairs, 1971-08-19; 29-07; 1.0 .mp3; 00:15:47; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; Wildcat, Nancy
  - Yuki expressions, 1953-07-23; 30-01; 1.0 .mp3; 01:05:55; Crawford, James Mack, 1925-; Logan, Frank; Melton, Robert; Swadesh, Morris, 1909-1967
    Round Valley Indian Reservation (Calif.); Yuki language